# Louise Pike Software Engineer

https://louise-pike.netlify.app/

https://github.com/stars/louisep1/lists/portfolio

# louisepike@live.co.uk

https://www.linkedin.com/in/louise-pike-82b2b9247/

# **Projects**

## Clean Hotels | React, MySQL, Sass

Using Sass/SCSS and React in the frontend and MySQL with Express in the backend, users can browse the page of this small chain of local hotels and make use of the backend functionality to check room availability and then make a reservation. https://clean-hotels.onrender.com

## Event Ticket Page | Node.js, Mongoose, Bootstrap

Using React with Bootstrap styling in the frontend and Mongoose and Express in the backend to connect to MongoDB, this full stack app allows users to buy and sell tickets to their favourite events.

https://event-ticket-page.onrender.com/

# Social Networking App | DaisyUI, Tailwind, React

The Social Network App is a mobile-first messaging page, built with Tailwind CSS and DaisyUI in the frontend, inspired by popular modern-day messaging services and designed for optimum use on a mobile device. Users can search for friends by email address and send messages.

https://social-network-app.onrender.com/

# **Summary**

Highly-motivated software engineer, specialising in full stack web development. As a developer, I enjoy the challenge of continually learning and solving problems and find great fulfillment in seeing code work as intended and in building new and inovative features.

# Skills

### Frontend:

JavaScript TypeScript CSS HTML Vue.js Vuex React React Router Redux Redux Toolkit Jest Sass/SCSS Bootstrap Tailwind CSS Daisy UI Axios

### **Backend:**

Node.js Express MySQL SQL MongoDB Mongoose JSON Web Token Bcrypt Socket.io

## **Additional tools/skills:**

GitHub/GitHub Desktop Postman HeidiSQL MySQL Workbench XAMPP phpMyAdmin MongoDB Compass Firebase/Firestore PayPal Sandbox Heroku Render Agile development Kanban

Japan

# **Work Experience**

# Software Engineer | Pyxos Corp

December 2022 to current

- Full stack engineer, developing and maintaining a web application in Japanese and English
- Project: online cloud-based vetenarian clinic management and reservation system the core of daily operations, used to store all client information and manage reservations and medical records/accounting/history in realtime.
- Tech stack: Frontend Vue.js with Vuex, TypeScript/JavaScript, Sass/SCSS, HTML. Backend Node.js with Express, TypeScript/JavaScript, connecting to MySQL database with Sequelize, operating in realtime with Socket.io. Unit test-oriented development wiith Jest.
- Implementing new features, fixing bugs, actively critically thinking about ways to improve the product to enhance the user experience, overseeing the whole process from design to production.
- Focus on working with values, time management and working as a team, using principles of agile software development, specifically kanban (trello) as a core framework.

# **Past Work Experience**

## **Educator | Yaruki Switch Group**

July 2019 to July 2022 (3 years)

- Teaching children with very little English experience and exposure.
- Focus on active language production.
- · Adept at working with clients (students) directly, face-to-face, considering their needs, goals and requirements.
- Worked within a diverse team of Japanese and international staff.

## **Nursery Manager | Tinysaurus Nurseries**

February 2018 to March 2019 (1 year)

- Started as a Trainee Manager, then Assistant Manager, then Nursery Manager, all within one year.
- Leadership of staff and overseeing tasks, officiating health and safety, delivering training, recruitment, marketing, ensuring customer satisfaction of the parents, and dealing with complains and issues.
- Able to deal with extreme pressure.

## Receptionist | Kicks Martial Arts Center

January 2016 to July 2019

- Part-time work as a receptionist at a local martial arts centre.
- Teamwork and communication were essential to this smaller, family-run business.

## **Activities Coordinator | Lyndhurst Rest Homes**

August 2016 to March 2017

• Organised activities for elderly residents in a care home. (Part-time)

# **Education History**



CELTA (Cambridge English Level 5 Certificate in Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages) | St Giles, Brighton

April – May 2019 Grade A Pass



MA International Education and Development | University of Sussex

Sept 2016 - Sept 2017 Merit

BA Childhood and Youth | University of Sussex

Sept 2013 - July 2016 First Class Honours

## Languages

**English Japanese**Native Conversational

## **Passions**

Dance Scuba diving Travel Outdoors Learning Japan

**Q** UK